Ethan J. Reimer

ereimer18@georgefox.edu | (253) 709-0006 | linkedin.com/in/ethanreimer | ethanreimer.com

Professional Summary

Highly motivated computer science major with a focus in cybersecurity. A devoted team member with leadership skills, dedication and experience working with a diverse variety of groups. Able to diligently perform a wide variety of tasks with key organizational skills and close attention to detail. Curious with a strong desire to take on projects offering new skills.

Education

George Fox University, Newberg, OR

Expected April 2022

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Cyber Security | GPA: 3.676

Relevant Courses: Data Structures, Digital Logic, Software Engineering, Computer Security and Digital Forensics, Object Oriented Analysis and Design, Analysis of Algorithms, Emerging Mobile Technologies, Database Systems, Data Communications and Networks, Computer Architecture/Assembly Languages, Servant Engineering, Operating Systems, Network Administration, Secure Software, Advanced Security, Structures of Programming Languages, Parallel and Distributed Computing, Web Development, Senior Design, Machine Learning (audit), Cyber Defense

Technical Skills

- Python
- Java
- C
- C++
- C#
- Ada
- Scala

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Git
- Docker
- SQL
- Linux Environment

- Virtual Machines
- Parallel Programming
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Cybersecurity
- Networking Protocols
- Shell Scripting

Collegiate Projects

- Senior Design HoloLens Augmented Reality Development (current): in conjunction with Daimler Trucks North America, my senior-design team is developing a Mixed Reality application for a Microsoft HoloLens using Unity and Microsoft's Mixed Reality Took Kit to provide a hands-free holographic solution for the intake process. This is aimed to improve efficiency through the use of voice control and gestures. We are exploring if Mixed Reality is a viable option in comparison with currently used platforms. I am acting as the technical manager on my team.
- Chess: Object-Oriented implementation of a command-line driven chess game.
- Servant Engineering Haptic Feedback Device: a haptic feedback device to aid visually impaired students in understanding a graphical image. My particular focus was in developing a color tracking program utilizing computer vision to track the user's hand movements across virtual space.
- Movie Database: applied database management practices and parsed old HTML and XML files to create and manage a PostgreSQL database.
- **Networking RFP:** drafted a bid in response to a hypothetical business Request for Proposal in my Data Communications and Networking course. Researched networking equipment and protocols necessary to put together a plan to restore a company to working order and improve network setup.

- Course Scheduler: for my Software Engineering course, my class split into teams to create a proof-of-concept course scheduling application to aid the George Fox academic departments in optimizing how courses are scheduled with as few conflicts between departments as possible. My team worked on the UI/UX aspect of the application, and we drafted several design options inspired by interviews with several faculty. My specific role was to draft a test matrix to run tests on the UI portion of the application. The development process focused on working with clients and using scrum and agile development techniques.
- Web Based Projects: see my personal website's landing page for the web-based projects I worked on for my web-based programming course: www.ethanreimer.com/landing.html
- Capture the Flag: a penetration testing exercise that I created with a peer as our final project utilizing steganography, PHP reverse shells and set-UID privilege escalation.

Work Experience

Barista, Chapters Books and Coffee, Newberg, ORAug 2021-presentDough Roller, Abby's Legendary Pizza, Newberg, ORJune 2021-Aug 2021Retail Associate, Lowes, Federal Way, WAJune 2020-Aug 2020Amazon Warehouse Associate, Amazon, Kent, WAMay 2019-July 2019

Extra-Curricular

- National Cyber League Contest Participant
 - o Spring 2021
 - o Fall 2021
 - Spring 2022 (expected)
- Oregon ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest Volunteer
 - o Fall 2018